Sam Middleton

Mechatronics Engineer | Web Developer

samdasquid@gmail.com | 022 083 5052 | LinkedIn | GitHub | NZ, US & UK citizen living in NZ

About Me

Hi, I'm a Mechatronics Engineer who graduated from the University of Canterbury in 2021 with 2:1 Honors. My recent experience at Dev Academy Aotearoa showed me that I can learn new things quickly and gave me lots of experience working in teams.

I have a passion for making things and figuring out how things work, and I love passing on what I've learnt to others. In my free time, I enjoy orienteering, board games, D&D and Magic the Gathering.

Experience

Full Stack Development Student | Dev Academy Aotearoa, Wellington

January 2023 - May 2023

A 17-week Web Development Bootcamp focusing on human skills and teamwork.

- I developed my teamwork skills through pair programming and regular projects in larger groups.
- Learnt Express, Knex, React, Redux, Superagent, Jest & Websockets

Computer Vision Engineer | Pisces Research Ltd, Wellington

March 2021 - Present

I developed a computer vision system for the semi-automated measurement of sampled fish for my Father's company and did some other random stuff.

• I developed my *presentation skills* by presenting my work to several groups of fishing industry professionals.

Engineer | Rangiora Bakery, Rangiora

November 2020 - February 2021 (Full-time Work Experience)

Bakery maintenance, repairs and design, fabrication and assembly of new tools and machines.

Factory Hand | Holyoake Industries Ltd, Wellington

November 2018 - February 2019 (Full-time Work Experience)

Assembly of many types of HVAC system parts

 I demonstrated organizational skills when tasked with sorting out what insulation we had and needed for a large order when some of the last sheets of insulation we had got miscut.

Mechatronics Engineering Student | University of Canterbury, Christchurch

February 2016 - July 2021

Included a Final Year Project for Airways NZ on ADS-B

Skills

Teamwork

Successfully worked in a team on numerous university and dev academy projects, and with six other volunteers on my Reach Out Volunteers expedition.

Communication

Wrote and gave numerous reports and presentations on many university assignments, especially on my final year project. Gave a presentation to my local Rotary branch about my experiences at the 2016 Rotary National Science and Technology Forum, after they sponsored my attendance.

Leadership

Led several adventure racing teams of varying sizes, most notably winning the mixed schools category in the 2015 Taranaki 6 Hour.

Organisation and Problem-Solving

When it was discovered that a batch of insulation panels for a large order had been incorrectly cut while I was working at Holyoake, I was assigned to work out what sizes of panels we had, how that compared to what we needed and how we could make the remaining panels out of the few remaining sheets of insulation stock and offcuts. I was able to ensure that we finished the order on time.

Education

New Zealand Certificate in Applied Software Development (Level 6) Dev Academy Aotearoa 2023

Bachelor of Engineering (Honors) in Mechatronics Engineering University of Canterbury 2016 - 2021 Second Class Honors, Division One

Referees available upon request